

□ (+1) 312-478-1131 | 🗷 abose4@uic.edu | 🌴 www.arindambose.com | 🖸 arindam-bose | 🛅 arindam-bose-75425417

2244 West Taylor Street, Fl. 1, Chicago, IL 60612, United States

Summary\_

Currently a Ph.D. candidate at Electrical and Computer Engineering Department, University of Illinois at Chicago and a research assistant at WaveOPT lab under Prof. Mojtaba Soltanalian. Research interests include signal processing and optimization theory, radar signal processing, active sensing, and theory of machine learning. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

KMB Telematics Arlington, VA, USA

SENIOR RESEARCH INTERN, FMCW RADAR DESIGN LAB

May 2019 - Aug. 2019

Developed efficient algorithms for designing antennas for FMCW automotive radar

### **Mitsubishi Electric Research Laboratories**

Cambridge, MA, USA

SUMMER INTERN, TERAHERTZ IMAGING LAB

May 2018 - Aug. 2018

Developed several efficient model based and machine learning algorithms for Time-Domain Spectroscopy systems using THz

### **University of Illinois at Chicago**

Chicago, IL, USA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, WAVEOPT LAB, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Jul. 2016 - Present

- · Developing several non-convex optimization algorithms for waveform design for smart active sensing systems
- Assisting and collaborating with Dr. M. Soltanalian in signal processing and optimization theory research and working towards PhD thesis

TEACHING ASSISTANT, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING AND DEPARTMENT OF PHYSICS

Aug. 2015 - Present

- Courses assisted: Digital signal processing, Statistical signal processing, Image analysis and computer vision, Introductory physics, General
  physics
- Collaborated with several professors to setup exam questions and answers
- · Graded papers, conducted lab sessions, and proctored examinations

### Cognizant Technology Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Kolkata, India

PROGRAMMER ANALYST, HEALTH CARE PRACTICE

Aug. 2014 - Apr. 2016

- Developed and maintained several Java based web projects according to client requests
- Designed web services and complex web pages in JSP, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Maintained PI and other health related client data in complex Oracle databases
- Developed and delivered special projects: Log Parser a log management system for complex bug reports, PBMAid an android app to track insurance related data for patients

# **Major Publications**

### **JOURNAL PAPERS**

# Joint Optimization of Waveform Covariance Matrix and Antenna Selection for MIMO Radar with an Application to Aerial Drones

A. Bose, S. Khobahi, and M. SoltanalianSubmitted in IEEE Transactions on Aerospace and Electronic Systems

2020

One-Bit Radar Processing With Time-Varying Sampling Thresholds

2019

· Published in IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing

# Constructing Binary Sequences With Good Correlation Properties: An Efficient Analytical-Computational Interplay

A. BOSE, M. SOLTANALIAN

· Published in IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing

### **CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS**

A. Ameri, A. Bose, J. Li, and M. Soltanalian

### **Deep One-Bit Compressive Autoencoder**

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Jul. 2020

S. Khobahi, **A. Bose**, and M. Soltanalian

• Submitted in IEEE Statistical Signal Processing Workshop (SSP) 2020

March 2, 2020 ARINDAM BOSE · RÉSUMÉ

### Deep-URL: A Model-Aware Approach to Blind Deconvolution Based on Deep Unfolded **Richardson-Lucy Network**

Abu Dhabi, UAE

Oct. 2020

Nov. 2019

C. AGARWAL, S. KHOBAHI, A. BOSE, M. SOLTANALIAN, AND D. SCHONFELD

• Submitted in IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP) 2020

**Deep Radar Waveform Design for Efficient Automotive Radar Sensing** 

Hangzhou, China

S. KHOBAHI, A. BOSE, AND M. SOLTANALIAN

A. BOSE, S. KHOBAHI, AND M. SOLTANALIAN

Jun. 2020

• Submitted in IEEE Sensor Array and Multichannel Signal Processing Workshop (SAM) 2020

Joint Optimization of Waveform Covariance Matrix and Antenna Selection for MIMO Radar

Pacific Grove, CA, USA

• Presented in IEEE Asilomar Conference on Signals, Systems, and Computers 2019

Waveform Design for One-Bit Radar Systems Under Uncertain Interference Statistics

Pacific Grove, CA, USA

A. Ameri, A. Bose, and M. Soltanalian

Nov. 2019

• Presented in IEEE Asilomar Conference on Signals, Systems, and Computers 2019

Learning-Based Shadow Mitigation for Terahertz Multi-Layer Imaging

Paris, France

P. Wang, T. Koike-Akino, **A. Bose**, R. Ma, P. Orlik, W. Tsujita, K. Sadamoto, H. Tsutada, and M. Soltanalian Presented in IEEE International Conference on Infrared, Millimeter, and Terahertz Waves (IRMMW-THz) 2019 Sep. 2019

THz Multi-Layer Imaging Via Nonlinear Inverse Scattering

Paris. France

A. Bose, A. Kadu, H. Mansour, P. Wang, P. Boufounos, P. Orlik, and M. Soltanalian

Sep. 2019

Presented in IEEE International Conference on Infrared, Millimeter, and Terahertz Waves (IRMMW-THz) 2019

Comprehensive Personalized Ranking Using One-Bit Comparison Data

Minneapolis, MN, USA

A. Ameri, **A. Bose**, and M. Soltanalian

Jun. 2019

Presented in IEEE Data Science Workshop (DSW) 2019

Design of Unimodular Sequence Sets with Good Correlation and Complementary Correlation **Properties** 

Anaheim, CA, USA

I. A. Arriaga-Trejo, A. Bose, A. G. Orozco-Lugo, and M. Soltanalian

Nov. 2018

Presented in 6th IEEE Global Conference on Signal and Information Processing (GlobalSIP) 2018, November 2018

**Designing Signals with Good Correlation and Distribution Properties** 

Calgary, AB, Canada

A. BOSE, N. MOHAMMADI, M. SOLTANALIAN

Apr. 2018

· Presenting in 43rd IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP), April 2018

## Education\_

### **University of Illinois at Chicago**

Chicago, IL, USA

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

2016 - 2020

- Thesis: Waveform synthesis for active sensing with emerging applications
- · Advisor: Dr. Mojtaba Soltanalian

# **West Bengal University of Technology**

Kolkata, India

B.Tech. IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

2008 - 2012

· Thesis: Efficient algorithms for digital watermarking

· Advisor: Dr. Somnath Maiti

### Skills

Programming Language MATLAB, Python, C, C++, Java

**Libraries** PyTorch, OpenCV

Web Designing JavaScript, CSS 3, HTML 5, JSP, JQuerry, PHP

**Database Management System** 

Oracle RDBMS, MySQL, PL/SQL, SQLite

Language

English, Hindi, Bengali